<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>raster on the Geocomputation with R website</title>
    <link>/tags/raster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in raster on the Geocomputation with R website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/raster/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hillshade maps</title>
      <link>/post/2020/hillshade-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/hillshade-maps/</guid>
      <description>This vignette builds on the making maps chapter of the Geocomputation with R book.
Prerequisites The example below assume the following packages are attached:
library(raster) # data download library(tmap) # map creation  Hillshade map Hillshade maps show the topographical shape of hills and mountains using levels of gray on a map. The role of this kind of maps is to display relative slopes, but not absolute height.
Calculate terrain characteristics Elevation data is needed to create a hillshade map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocomputation for sea level research</title>
      <link>/post/2020/sea-level-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/sea-level-rise/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Sea level rise (SLR) is a global phenemona whose impacts vary geographically. Although the sea rises everywhere (although at different rates), only certain, low-lying locations will be affected. Sea level research involves analysing large geographic datasets and statistical models of change, making the computational approach advocated in Geocomputation with R well-suited to its study.
The main factors determining the spatial distribution include elevation, proximity to the sea and population density: large, low-lying coastal settlements house the highest numbers of people at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>