<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sf on the Geocomputation with R website</title>
    <link>https://geocompr.github.io/tags/sf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sf on the Geocomputation with R website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geocompr.github.io/tags/sf/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geocomputation with R: Second Edition feedback</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/geocompr2-bp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/geocompr2-bp1/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Please help us by filling out the survey at https://forms.gle/nq9RmbxJyZXQgc948.
It’s been almost 3 years since the first edition of Geocomputation with R was published back in 2019. It’s been an amazing journey for this open source book on geographic data analysis, visualization and modeling since then. We have reached almost 500k people via the website at https://geocompr.robinlovelace.net/ and the physical book. The book now contributes to many university courses, lectures, and personal development as outlined at https://geocompr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversions between different spatial classes in R</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/spatial-classes-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/spatial-classes-conversion/</guid>
      <description>The R programming language has, over the past two decades, evolved substantial spatial data analysis capabilities, and is now one of the most powerful environments for undertaking geographic research using a reproducible command line interface. Currently, dedicated R packages allow to read spatial data and apply a plethora of different kinds of spatial methods in a reproducible fashion.
There are two main1 spatial data models - spatial vector data and spatial raster data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent changes in R spatial and how to be ready for them</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2020/whyr_webinar004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2020/whyr_webinar004/</guid>
      <description>Currently, hundreds of R packages are related to spatial data analysis. They range from ecology and earth observation, hydrology and soil science, to transportation and demography. These packages support various stages of analysis, including data preparation, visualization, modeling, or communicating the results. One common feature of most R spatial packages is that they are built upon some of the main representations of spatial data in R, available in key geographic R packages such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo of reproducible geographic data analysis: mapping Covid-19 data with R</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2020/mapping-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2020/mapping-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The coronavirus pandemic is a global phenomenon that will affect the lives of the majority of the world’s population for years to come. Impacts range from physical distancing measures already affecting more than half of Earth’s population and knock-on impacts such as changes in air quality to potentially life threatening illness, with peer reviewed estimates of infection fatality rates showing the disease disproportionately affects the elderly and people with underlying health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic projections and transformations</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/crs-projections-transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/crs-projections-transformations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This workbook outlines key concepts and functions related to map projections — also referred to as coordinate reference systems (CRSs) — and transformation of geographic data from one projection to another. It is based on the open source book Geocomputation with R, and Chapter 6 in particular.
It was developed for the ‘CASA Summer School’, or the Doctoral Summer School for Advanced Spatial Modelling: Skills Workshop and Hackathon, 21st to 23rd August 2019, for its full name!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
