<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sabre on the Geocomputation with R website</title>
    <link>https://geocompr.github.io/tags/sabre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sabre on the Geocomputation with R website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geocompr.github.io/tags/sabre/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geocomputation with R: Second Edition feedback</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/geocompr2-bp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/geocompr2-bp1/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Please help us by filling out the survey at https://forms.gle/nq9RmbxJyZXQgc948.
It’s been almost 3 years since the first edition of Geocomputation with R was published back in 2019. It’s been an amazing journey for this open source book on geographic data analysis, visualization and modeling since then. We have reached almost 500k people via the website at https://geocompr.robinlovelace.net/ and the physical book. The book now contributes to many university courses, lectures, and personal development as outlined at https://geocompr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversions between different spatial classes in R</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/spatial-classes-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2021/spatial-classes-conversion/</guid>
      <description>The R programming language has, over the past two decades, evolved substantial spatial data analysis capabilities, and is now one of the most powerful environments for undertaking geographic research using a reproducible command line interface. Currently, dedicated R packages allow to read spatial data and apply a plethora of different kinds of spatial methods in a reproducible fashion.
There are two main1 spatial data models - spatial vector data and spatial raster data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
