<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rspatial on the Geocomputation with R website</title>
    <link>https://geocompr.github.io/tags/rspatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rspatial on the Geocomputation with R website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geocompr.github.io/tags/rspatial/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demo of reproducible geographic data analysis: mapping Covid-19 data with R</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/wip/mapping-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/wip/mapping-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The coronavirus pandemic is a global phenomenon that will affect the lives of the majority of the world’s population for years to come. Impacts range from physical distancing measures already affecting more than half of Earth’s population and knock-on impacts such as changes in air quality to potentially life threatening illness, with peer reviewed estimates of infection fatality rates showing the disease disproportionately affects the elderly and people with underlying health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing spatial R packages on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2020/installing-r-spatial-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2020/installing-r-spatial-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>This post explains how to quickly get key R packages for geographic research installed on Ubuntu, a popular Linux distribution.
A recent thread on the r-spatial GitHub organization alludes to many considerations when choosing a Linux set-up for work with geographic data, ranging from the choice of Linux distribution (distro) to the use of binary vs or compiled versions (binaries are faster to install). This post touches on some of these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inset maps with ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/ggplot2-inset-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/ggplot2-inset-maps/</guid>
      <description>Inset maps enable multiple places to be shown in the same geographic data visualisation, as described in the Inset maps section (8.2.7) of our open source book Geocomputation with R. The topic of inset maps has gained attention and recently Enrico Spinielli asked inset maps could be created for data in unusual coordinate systems:
Speaking of insets, do you know of any ggplot2 examples with an inset for showing where the (bbox of the) map is in an orthographic/satellite proj?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map coloring: the color scale styles available in the tmap package</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/tmap-color-scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/tmap-color-scales/</guid>
      <description>This vignette builds on the making maps chapter of the Geocomputation with R book. Its goal is to demonstrate all possible map styles available in the tmap package.
Prerequisites The examples below assume the following packages are attached:
library(spData) # example datasets library(tmap) # map creation library(sf) # spatial data reprojection The world object containing a world map data from Natural Earth and information about countries’ names, regions, and subregions they belong to, areas, life expectancies, and populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grids and graticules in the tmap package</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/tmap-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/tmap-grid/</guid>
      <description>This vignette builds on the making maps chapter of the Geocomputation with R book. Its goal is to demonstrate how to set and modify grids and graticules in the tmap package.
Prerequisites The examples below assume the following packages are attached:
library(spData) # example datasets library(tmap) # map creation (&amp;gt;=2.3) library(sf) # spatial data classes  Grids and graticules The tmap package offers two ways to draws coordinate lines - tm_grid() and tm_graticules().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic projections and transformations</title>
      <link>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/crs-projections-transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geocompr.github.io/post/2019/crs-projections-transformations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This workbook outlines key concepts and functions related to map projections — also referred to as coordinate reference systems (CRSs) — and transformation of geographic data from one projection to another. It is based on the open source book Geocomputation with R, and Chapter 6 in particular.
It was developed for the ‘CASA Summer School’, or the Doctoral Summer School for Advanced Spatial Modelling: Skills Workshop and Hackathon, 21st to 23rd August 2019, for its full name!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
